Daniele Castrovilli

BioInformatic



Contact Via Bolzano, 5 Verona 37135 Italy

+39 342-0343653

E-mail
Web Site
GitHub: xcloudx8

About me

Graduate in bioinformatics (Bachelor and master degrees) at the University of Verona acquiring skills in the field of data analysis, and their manipulation. I implemented databases for genomes and data retrieving from them with PHP, and i learned programming languages such as Python, C, PHP, SQL, Matlab. My final project was the analysis, by means of proteomic data, the murine cells infected with acute myeloid leukoencephalopathy treated with pantethine IN vivo and EX vivo. After i worked as a bioinformatics at the hospital in Verona (AOUI) for the analysis of data from patients with cerebrovascular insufficiency. At last i've analyzed data obtained from devices created within the group at OpenBioMedical intiative as a volunteer. As master degree thesis i worked on developing a data warehouse supporting genomic analyses, grating the storage, manipulation and data interpretation of allelic variant files. Actually i'm a business intelligence analyst at Trueblue S.R.L. working on data warehouse for pharmaceutical industries interpreting and analyzing business core data.

Education

2004-2010	High school degree in Scientific studies	Liceo scientifico A. Vallone, Galatina(LE)
10/2010 - 03/2013	Bachelor degree in Bioinformatic	Universita' degli studi di Verona, Verona
10/2014 - 03/2017	Master degree in Bioinformatic and medical biotechnology, Bioinformatic curriculum Universita' degli studi di Verona, Verona	

Skills:

Languages

- · Italian mother tongue
- English fluency
- French fluency

Programming skills

- ♥ Python
- SQL
- PHP
- JAVA
- C
- Matlab
- · CSS3 & HTML5

Software skills

- ♥ Atom Editor
- Github
- Matlab
- Microsoft Excel
- Pentaho
- MySQL
- PostgreSQL
- Microsoft SQL Integration Service
- Microsoft SQL Reporting Service
- · Microsoft SQL Server Management

Experience

Working experiences

Nov 2016 - Attuale

Business Intelligence analyst

Trueblue S.R.L.

Working at Trueblue S.r.l. as Business Intelligence Analyst.

With the aid of big data we give useful business information to pharmaceutical business.

Detailed achievements:

- Data manipulation
- Data interpretation
- Pharmaceutical business core management
- MS SQL Server Integration Service, MS SQL Server Reporting Service, MS SQL Server Management

Universita' degli studi di Verona

Sept 2012-Feb 2013

Probabilistic technique for studying multiple sclerosis with proteomic data Universita'

degli studi di Verona, Bachelor degree final project

Bioinformatic

We have studied the effects of the vitamin B5 on murine cell growth both IN vivo and EX vivo and studied the effects with and without the vitamin Detailed achievements:

- · Learned how to manage huge file in excel
- Learned how to use MATLAB for data manipulation

Dec 2015-Mar 2015

Analysis on bacteriophages and analysis on similarities between viruses attacking same bacteria. Universita' degli studi di Verona

Bioinformatic

In this work we have analyzed the similarities between the genomes of the viruses and the specific host bacteria , and highlight any similarities between different virus genomes but attacking the same species of bacterium. the genomes of 300 bacteria and bacteriophages in 1000 were analyzed , with automation through bash shell scripts , python and analysis through IGTools . Detailed achievements:

- · Learned how to manipulate data with bash shell scripting
- · Learned how to use SED, GREP, AWK for data analysis
- · Learned how to read and interpret huge amount of data

Sept 2015-Mar 2016

Report generator *Bioinformatic*

Universita' degli studi di Verona

Software for creating a simple pdf file from genomic analysis with NGS for a patient report, it is written in Python combining the typographic power of Latex. Detailed achievements:

- · Learned how to manage an entire project in Python
- · Learned how to use GITHUB
- Learned teamwork
- Learned use of web parsers

Sept 2015-Mar 2016

Variant database

Universita' degli studi di Verona

Bioinformatic

Creation of a simple database written in MySQL and PHP $\,$

Detailed achievements:

- · Learned better SQL language
- Learned how to use MySQL, PostgreSQL
- Learned PHP
- Learned HTML and CSS3 usage of data retrieval

Sept 2016-Mar 2017

Modeling and implementing a data warehouse to support genomic analyses Universita'

degli studi di Verona

Bioinformatico

Developing of adata warehouse to help genomic analyses and to create a big data support to genomic laboratory of University of Verona.

Detailed achievements:

- · Better skills in SQL language
- Learned use of PENTAHO SOFTWARE SUITE, POSTGRESQL
- How to read genomic data files
- · Understandings of statistical data

AOUI, Universitary hospital of Verona

Jul 2016-Oct 2016 Bioinformatic support for data mining

AOUI hospital, Verona

Bioinformatic

Manipulation, extraction and data visualization about a wide range of data,

from metabolic syndrom to child obesity

Detailed achievements:

Learned how to extract useful data and make it understandable with visualization

Apr 2013-Jul 2013

Genome-wide association for metabolic syndrome

AOUI hospital, Verona

Bioinformatic

Analysis with bioinformatic tools on patients affected by metabolic syndrome Detailed achievements:

- · Learned how to read genetic population data
- Learned basic usege of PLINK

May 2013-Jul 2013 **GWAAS Database Help**

AOUI hospital, Verona

Bioinformatic

Analysis and creation of genetic databases with Hapmap for GWAAS analysis Detailed achievements:

- Learned how to use HapMap
- Learned better BASH SHELL SCRIPTING

Volunteering

Valunteer **OpenBioMedical Initiative**

Nowhere

Bioinformatic

Support on developing source code and being a Bioinformatic consultant

Detailed achievements:

Learned better team management and teamworking

Volunteer Ubuntu translator / Bug Tracker

Nowhere

Volunteer

Support on translating strings in Ubuntu OS and bug discovery. Detailed

achievements:

Learned how to translate softwares

Learned better HOW A COMMUNITY WORKS

Volunteer AISM

Nowhere

Volunteer

Volunteer on the AISM association as care giver

Disclaimers:

This CV has been made entirelly with LaTeX